Hi everyone.
Now I'll show several interesting experiments.
So, the receiving and transmitting coils are ready.
This is the receiving Tesla coil.
The load will be a 15W lamp, diode bridge, capacitor.
Measurement will do by DC.
This is our voltmeter.
So, first test launch in continuous generation mode.
Generation, as usual, all starts without any interruptions.
In this mode, we have the consumption of the control logic part.
This lab block will record the power consumption of the common system.
I now raise the current, voltage I regulated.
The system doesn't even start because of very strong influence from receiving coil onto transmitting.
Need to step them apart a little.
Now I approach.
See, the current grew for us.
And what do we observe?
As usual, the fluorescent lamp glows.
The lamp doesn't glow for us.
Near the transmitting Tesla, the fluorescent lamp glows very poorly, and near the receiving it glows well.
This is already interesting.
Now look what we have on transmitting first.
There's actually nothing here.
Only touching on the receiving.
On receiving, it's livelier.
See the discharge.
You can see that non-chlorobe melts from the discharge, drops flow.
Such a hot Tesla came out.
Well, and that's it.
We won't get more besides the interesting moment you could see here.
For some reason on the receiving Tesla, we have much more field and much higher voltage.
Experiment number two.
I disconnected the lamp and disconnected grounding the inductor from its middle point.
Now we'll do modulation with frequency 50 hertz.
The modulating pulse duration for us is 1%.
I switched the system to modulation mode.
This is consumption of the logic control part.
Now I raise the supply voltage.
This consumption we record now.
Electrolytic at input 470F.
I apply 200V to the system.
You hear the characteristic 50 hertz sound.
It even echoes from above in the rafters.
Look at the voltage on the transmitting part.
Breakdown distance.
Breakdown starts about 5 centimeters.
The receiving part.
Breakdown at distance of 10 to 12 centimeters.
Now we'll do the same manipulation.
Pay attention to consumption.
We clearly have a voltage excess on the receiving coil.
Once more transmitting.
Here at least two times lower.
And this is already an interesting phenomenon.
We created a vortex with interruption help.
And energy already went to the receiving Tesla transformer.
So, experiment number three.
I connected the lamp.
Connected grounding to the inductor middle point.
What will we record at this experiment input?
We'll record that we have a load.
The lamp will glow.
And we'll have voltage excess on the Tesla transformer itself.
The inductor is now wound.
As they say, randomly.
First available.
By length I didn't pick it.
That'll need to be done later.
Just to show the essence that the system can simultaneously give and still have a reserve.
Also for us the interruption will go at frequency 50 hertz.
At duration 1 percent.
Here 50 hertz.
I raise voltage on the transmitting Tesla.
Also 200 V.
So, you see the lamp lit.
Voltage on the lamp is 150 V, 155, slightly higher.
I checked.
And if voltage on this lamp is 150 V, it burns exactly at half glow.
A 15 V lamp at 7.5 V.
Consumption.
Common system.
See the voltage on the transmitting part.
Break down about 5 centimeters on the receiving.
Break down now about 8 centimeters.
An interesting phenomenon turns out.
We load the receiving Tesla transformer with some load, take power off, and it has a voltage amplitude excess on the secondary coil relative to the primary.
And now we have the consumption.
How much is it there?
Twice 8, 16.
It turns out for us that the system consumes 16 V, 7.5 V output, and excess on the secondary coil.
That is, what's the conclusion?
That in the system, we must use modulations.
This is the most usual modulation, now without any phase shifts.
The check of this experiment is that with the coordination of two systems, they're now tuned.
The transmitting and receiving coils are identical, tuned to one and the same frequency.
That is, parameters maintained.
And we have such an interesting effect.
This is the answer to the question people ask.
Can there be more energy on the receiving Tesla transformer than on the transmitting?
In modulation mode, naturally, yes.
If the Tesla transformer starts just in mode without modulation, you will see that the you won't see such effects, or they'll be weak as I showed in experiment number one.
Make conclusions yourselves, and we work further.